today we're going to talk about ai image
generators and we're going to try to
understand how they work when i say ai
image generators i'm talking
specifically about open ai's daily 2 and
google's imaging they're both ai's that
will generate a photorealistic image
from a text input and the results are
mind blowing valley 2 will give us this
image if we input the text an astronaut
riding a horse in a photo realistic
style or if we write teddy bears
shopping for groceries in ancient egypt
we won't only get an image like this one
which is one of my favorites but we will
also get different variations as well
google's imaging is equally or more
impressive than dali 2 according to
google's researchers in terms of image
quality with the input a photo of a
raccoon wearing an astronaut helmet
looking out of the window at night
imaging comes up with this
or if we input the text a dragon fruit
wearing a karate belt in the snow we
will receive a picture like this one as
you can see both dali and imaging are
equally mind-blowing but where imagine
might have an edge over dali tu is on
drawing text when asked to create a sign
that says burger king or welcome dal e2
makes images that look real except they
don't have the correct text in them
in contrast google's imaging seems to be
able to draw text without a problem with
the input of sprouts in the shape of
text imaging coming out of a fairy tale
book the output looks pretty good keep
in mind that since google hasn't allowed
public access to imaging this might be a
cherry picked example that might not
hold true after a lot of testing both of
these ais seem to work better with
longer text inputs the prompt to imaging
for this image is an art gallery
displaying monet paintings the art
gallery is flooded robots are going
around the art gallery using paddle
boards
as you can see imaging delivered very
well and the prompt to daily2 for this
image was a shipping container with
solar panels on top and a propeller on
one end that can drive through the ocean
by itself the self-driving shipping
container is driving under the golden
gate bridge during a beautiful sunset
with dolphins jumping all around it as
long as hell and dali delivered it only
missed on the dolphins because they're
not there but actually if you zoom in to
the propeller of the ship you can see a
tiny little dolphin tail there i could
personally look at images made by dali
or imagine all they because it's
mind-blowing and mesmerizing what these
ais can do imagine people that make
animations movies or video games
prototyping their ideas using this kind
of ai's we could also say that thanks to
this kind of ais like daddy 2 and imogen
the idea of humans being out of a job
because of ai can become a reality
pretty pretty soon in the case of daddy
2 and imaging there may be a direct
threat to graphic designers or
photographers now of course in the case
of photographers or designers maybe they
will be able to use this ai as a tool to
make their job faster and better but i
can also see companies that prefer to
use ai generated images for their
website rather than hiring a
photographer for example imagine a
fashion brand taking a daily generated
image like this one right here and
putting it on a shirt now since i have a
very peculiar style of shirts as you can
realize i would probably end up buying
that shirt whether it was made by human
or an ai the fashion brand would have
reduced the human cost and the designer
would have not been needed at all that
reality is inspiring and scary at the
same time so many questions come up for
example who owns the copyright of the
image is it the person that wrote the
text is it the company that trained the
ai is it the artist whose image was used
to train the ai or how easy is it to
know if an image presented in the court
of law was created using an ai now it
makes sense why google and open ai
haven't actually released these apis
with 100 public access for everybody to
use because the consequences might not
be so good now let's move on to see a
little bit of how daddy 2 works from the
inside this won't be an in-depth
explanation of everything but instead
what i want to do is just see what are
the ingredients that make up that it
doing how sort of works so we can see
that there is no magic involved it's
actually the work brains and mass of
some of the most brilliant people around
to understand how valley 2 works we
first need to talk about clip which is a
model that some people say is
revolutionizing computer vision computer
vision is a field of ai that focuses on
how computers can extract information
from images and video
usually what we are used to seeing in
computer vision are ais that label
images you show them a photo and they
can tell you if there is a cat or house
or a horse clip is different in that it
doesn't label images instead clip is
able to relate images with their correct
image caption now captions and labels
are different a label is like a house a
cut a door a face and models that use
labels require a lot of human effort in
labeling each photo to be able to train
the model an image caption in contrast
is something like two people sitting on
the beach in the sunset the advantage of
training your model with captions over
labels is that you don't need humans to
caption the images because there are
many images already with their captions
in news websites in blogs and instagram
is full of image caption pairs now clip
was trained with 4 million of these
image and caption pairs so clip is very
good as we said at taking an image and
choosing the right caption for the image
which is the opposite of what dali does
what opening i wanted was to take a
caption and return an image doing an
unclip basically reversing the clip
process to understand it's better let's
see how clip was trained how does it see
images and captions and how it knows
when a caption corresponds to an image
clip has two encoders an image encoder
and a text encoder the text encoder and
the image encoder transform the text and
the image into something called
embeddings which are vectors of numbers
vectors you can imagine them like long
arrays these vectors are the
mathematical representation of the text
and the image for example and this isn't
a real example just to illustrate the
point if we had these images and we
turned these images into vectors using
our custom image encoder let's say that
we get something like this the first
item of the array is a score of how cute
the image is the second one is how
lovely and the third one is how hairy
with this vector representation of our
images the computer will know that the
first and last image are closer to each
other than closer to the second image
now of course the vectors that clip
makes have way more dimensions than our
example because they extract all sorts
of features from the text and the images
after clip has the text and the image
embeddings which remember is just a
mathematical representation of both of
them it will try to find the text
vectors or embeddings that are closer to
the image vectors or embeddings as well
now back to dali too when we write an
input for dali clip will be used to
generate only the text embeddings which
means the mathematical representation of
those words those embeddings the array
of numbers the vectors that is given to
a model called the prior model prior
model will take this text embeddings and
will output image embeddings so it's
basically taking the mathematical
representation of a sentence and
generating from that sentence the
mathematical representation of an image
finally the image embeddings are given
to a decoder that has the job of turning
image embeddings into an actual image
this decoder and also the prior that we
talked about before are both something
called diffusion models when training a
diffusion model this model will take an
image and slowly step by step add noise
to it until the image is lost not
visible and then it learns to fix that
image by removing the noise step by step
until it arrives to the initial state of
the image effectively fixing it this is
the model in charge of taking those
image embeddings and turning them into
something that humans can actually see
now if your head spinning don't worry
mine is also as well explaining and
understanding all this is very hard
especially because open ai hasn't open
source valley too it's close to source
so we cannot look at the code and see
what techniques and what is opening are
doing under the hood but nevertheless
open ai's dali 2 and google's imaging
are both gigantic leaps of progress on
the fields of natural language
processing computer vision image
generation basically ai as a whole which
is something that thanks to the sponsor
of this video you can learn as well
naver connect foundation is recruiting
250 people to join a free ai education
program called boost camp ai tech boost
camp ai tech is an intensive program
that runs for five months monday to
friday from 10 a.m to 7 00 p.m covering
a to set of ai production students will
start learning from the very basics and
then they will get to choose from three
tracks computer vision natural language
processing and recommendation systems
the program consists of projects
designed with real life data and
problems allowing the students to
experience development of ai models with
real life tasks
so by the end of the 20 weeks students
will be able to make an ai model into an
actual service that can be distributed
and used by people the program will
provide high-powered gpus to students
there will be 82 mentors to help you and
there will be also 30 to 40 business
partners to help and guide students also
there will be various community events
and peer sessions to enable students to
grow within the developer community this
program is a hundred percent free and
anyone can apply but only those with a
strong passion and will to learn will be
accepted applications are open right now
and there is not a lot of time left so
click the link below to apply and be
part of the program thank you as always
for watching let me know what do you
think of this video on the comments and
what videos you would like to see next
stay happy stay free it's kimchi santa
see you on the next one bye